ANTHONY DOAN

Senior Android Engineer

408-630-5594 tony.p.doan@gmail.com

30747 Bloomfest Street Murrieta, CA 92563

PROFILE

Successfully contributing to your company's projects for services and products, to develop positive long lasting professional relationships within your company, and to mature into an essential asset and vital resource for your company are my primary focuses. I have achieved a Master of Science in Computer Science and have gained a diverse and significant amount of professional experience throughout life. I am a successful team player, however, I am also effective at working independently. I have a passion for working with people, for problem solving, and for enjoying the social culture of the work environment. I am a productive worker, a reliable team player,

and a very approachable character with a cheerful personality.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Android Engineer, Evite Inc; Los Angeles, CA - February 2022 - September 2023

Evite's focus is to manage social events through digital invitations with creative card designs and mobile event management. Through this social platform, hundreds of thousands of events are created and managed yearly. I led the effort to rewrite the entire app as the primary developer through 8 phases including app screens for home, my events, gallery, categories, account, invitation create flow, greeting cards, and add guests. Kotlin, Dagger, Retrofit, Core Android libraries, and Jet Pack libraries were leveraged to create an entire new experience for this successful social platform.

Play Store URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.evite&hl=en_US&gl=US&pli=1

Senior Android Engineer, Beachbody Inc; Santa Monica, CA - April 2021 - January 2022

Beachbody strives to improve fitness and nutrition for its users. At Beachbody, I focused on developing BODi, their new collaborative and interactive live fitness exercise experience. Audio and video streams were managed real-time to provide this virtual group experience conducted in a special studio by professional trainers. The Android app is extensive with communication, video,

nutrition, and admin components. During my time here, I utilized advanced Android technologies.

Play Store URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.beachbody.bod&hl=en US&gl=US

Senior Android Engineer, Insulet Corporation; San Diego, CA - January 2020 - March 2021

Helping diabetics live healthy and happy lives is the focus for Insulet Corporation. During my time here, I focused on introducing "app time" to the OmniPod 5 insulin pump system. Time in the app is used in over 190 places within the app and now we differentiate between app time and device time. This new app time feature had many implications for the delivery of insulin by our Bluetooth insulin pump. I led the effort for this project and it allowed me to learn this advanced solution by this medical device company.

Play Store URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.insulet.myblue.pdm&hl=en_US&gl=US

Senior Android Engineer, WalMart Labs Inc; Carlsbad, CA - March 2019 - January 2020

- WalMart Labs delivers over \$50 billion dollars of groceries to millions of its users annually. My time here was focused on the Capital One project where Capital One assumed all the WalMart debt from their credit cards previously owned by Synchrony Bank. WalMart had to handle this migration within the Android app and I focused on that migration. Requirements included messaging the Android users, rendering new user interface elements, processing new Bank Identification Numbers, modifying the checkout flow to accommodate Capital One, and automate the validation of all new Capital One cards.

Play Store URL:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details? id=com.walmart.android&hl=en_US&gl=US

Senior Android Engineer, Netgear & Arlo Inc; Carlsbad, CA - December 2015 - August 2016; May 2017 - March 2019

I worked as a senior developer for the Arlo Android mobile app that works in conjunction with the Netgear Arlo Home Security System sold at Best Buy, Target and Amazon. I oversaw the development for the following projects - app support

for Ultra cameras, Common Account Manager, Device Capabilities, Bridge and Lights, and Pet Tracker. Arlo's solutions have many components including mobile apps, Internet devices like camera and lights, base stations and bridges, and Cloud subsystems within the technology platform and eco-system.

Play Store URL: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.arlo.app&hl=en_US&gl=US

Senior iOS Engineer, AudaExplore Inc; San Diego, CA - January 2014 - October 2014

I worked on mobile solutions that provided insurance estimations for car repairs based on photos taken from the user's iPhone along with damage data indicated through interactions with animated car vehicles rendered with the Unity framework. Customers are able to get parts and labor estimates within 24 hours of an accident using our mobile platform.

EDUCATION

Portland State University, Portland, OR — Master of Science, Computer Science, 2009

Portland State University, Portland, OR — Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, 2003

SKILLS

* Smartphone Platforms

- Experienced with both **Android** and **iOS** platforms.
- Moderate experience with **BlackBerry** and **Symbian** platforms.
- Languages used are Kotlin, JAVA, Objective-C, and Swift
- Integrated Development Environments used are **Android Studio** and **Xcode**.
- Jet Packs core libraries
- Fingerprint and Biometric API
- Dagger, Koin, and Butterknife for dependency injection
- Room, Realm, and SQLite local databases
- Retrofit and OKHttp network frameworks
- SourceTree, Desktop GitHub, and Android Studio for Git clients
- Android integration of Accessibility through TalkBack and screen readers
- Test automation with Mockito, Junit, and Appium
- Use of design patterns such as MVVM, Adapter, Dependency Injection, Factory, Singleton
- ConstraintLayout and Jet Packs Compose for UI development

* Microsoft .NET Technologies

- Experienced with the .NET Framework's APIs, ASP.NET, C# programming language, JScript, ADO.NET
- Developed three projects while at WebMD with the above listed Microsoft Technologies.
 Fully certified in MCAD (Microsoft Certified Application Developer).

* Programming Languages

- A settled developer in: Kotlin, C#, JAVA, C++, C, PERL, PHP, JavaScript, Objective-C.
- Employed the use of C# in WebMD's MS Health Manager sponsored by Serono.
- Wrote a proto-type client-server application with JAVA's network API.
- Created, maintained, and enhanced web sites written in PHP and PERL.
- Implemented a complete compiler for a Pascal-like language called PCAT in the C language.
 Made interactive user interfaces for web applications with JavaScript.

* Databases

- Working knowledge of: Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, TSQL, POSTGRESQL, Firebase and SQL.
- Wrote stored procedures and user defined functions to provide database layer support to the application layer.
- Experienced in writing efficient queries in SQL.

* Protocols

- Familiar with various protocols: HTTP, HTTPS, FTP, TCP, UDP, IP
- Implemented a custom made FTP client that featured the most common functions used in file transfer.
- Produced a client-server application in C that communicated with an extended network protocol which I designed, named RUP and derived from UDP.

* Software Processes

- Working experience in a business environment that utilizes strong methodologies and policies to control development. Worked within a well-defined release cycle where milestones, software phases, and implementation practices for developers enforced timely product delivery and successful evolution of the software to later, improved versions.